Nestor D. Pereira Neto

FLECTRONIC ENGINEER : 36

Street Eduardo Campos nº 10, Boca do Rio, Salvador - BA, Brazil, 41705-230

■ (71) 9 9698-6755 | ■ nestor-dp@hotmail.com | ● lattes.cnpq.br/8490310764316084 | ■ nestorpneto | • NestorDP

"I have a degree in Electronic Engineering (2013) and a specialization in Biomedical Engineering (2019). I have experience in the maintenance of diagnostic imaging hospital equipment. In 2011, I started to work as a teacher in technical and higher education courses. I am currently finishing my Masters in Electrical Engineering at the Federal University of Bahia in the area of computing and robotics. Since 2019 I have had the pleasure of working in research and development in the field of robotics. Main areas of interest: Hardware decription, Hardware an software integration, C/C++ Programming; Embedded systems; Real-time systems and Mobile robotics localization and navigation."

Education

Federal University of Bahia - UFBA

Salvador, BA

MASTER'S DEGREE IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING - RESEARCH LINE: COMPUTING AND ROBOTICS

Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2022

- Communication between Robot Operating System ROS and System-on-a-chip SoC with integrated FPGA.
- Scholarship from Higher Education Personal Improvement Coordination CAPES

Estácio de Sá University

Salvador, BA

SPECIALIZATION IN BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING

Oct. 2017 - Feb. 2019

• Convolutional Neural Network for Detection of QRS Complexes in Electrocardiogram Signals

Faculty of Science and Technology - ÁREA1

Salvador, BA

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING

Feb. 2008 - Jul. 2013

- · Command prototype to fit X-ray equipment to the standards required by the National Health Surveillance Agency ANVISA.
- Undergraduate research scholarship for two years

Professional Experiences

SENAI - CIMATEC Salvador, BA

SPECIALIST II - ROBOTIC ENGINEERING

Apr. 2022 - currently

- ROS2 robotics framework: Gazebo Simulation, URDF/Xacro, SLAM Techniques for UGV.
- Programming C/C++ and python.
- Hardware and software integration.
- Hardware and firmware development for embedded systems.

CONSULTANT II - ROBOTIC ENGINEERING

Apr. 2019 - Apr. 2022

- ROS robotics framework: Gazebo Simulation, URDF/Xacro.
- Programming C/C++ and python.
- · Hardware and software integration.
- Hardware and firmware development for embedded systems.

PROFESSOR PART TIME - 20H

Nov. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- Teach class for the course: Industrial Mechatronics.
- Subjects: Analog Electronics and Digital Eletronic.

ÁREA1|Wyden College Salvador, BA

LABORATORY TECHNICIAN

Jul. 2013 - Aug. 2017

- Prepare and teach practical classes for the courses: Computer Engineering, Electrical Engineering and Automation Engineering.
- · Test new tools used in laboratories and provide training.
- Provide extension courses and the experience program.

Alfamed Eletromedicina

Salvador, BA

Engineer - Technical responsible

Aug. 2013 - Feb. 2015

Technical responsible for the company.Electronic maintenance in hospital bio-imaging equipment.

Centro Territorial de Educação Profissional da Região Metropolitana CETEP-RM

Camaçari, BA jun. 2011 - jun. 2013

TEACHER - 40H

NOVEMBER 16, 2022

• Teach classes in the following subjects: Analog and digital electronics; Microcontrollers; Electric circuits.

· Guide students in their course completion work.

Nestor D. Pereira Neto · Curriculum Vitae

Jun. 2009 - Sep. 2010

MAINTENANCE TECHNICIAN

· Preventive and corrective maintenance in hospital bioimaging equipment.

INTERN - MAINTENANCE Mar. 2008 - Jun. 2009

• Preventive and corrective maintenance in hospital bioimaging equipment.

Languages_

Portuguese Native.

English B1 level - CERF.

Courses

2022	English lessons (weekly), Private course	Salvador, BA
2021	FPGA INTEL Training(20h), Macnica DHW - Official Training Center FPGA INTEL	Florianópolis, SC
2018	NucLi - English. listening comprehension (32h), Federal University of Bahia - UFBA	Salvador, BA
2018	Programa Idiomas sem Fronteiras: My English Online - Level 4 (120h), Ministry of Education - MEC.	Brasil
2010	Study of Device Control via parallel, serial and USB ports (60h), Faculdade ÁREA1.	Salvador, BA
2010	Applied Analog Electronics (30h), Faculdade ÁREA1.	Salvador, BA

Projects and Research

SENAI CIMATEC Salvador, BA

SuBot - CTG Brasil (China Three Gorges Corporation)

Out. 2021 - Atualmente

- Mobile robotics development project for inspection of high voltage substations.
- Development of ROS nodes in C/C++ and Python language.
- · Hardware and firmware development for actuator systems and peripheral communication.
- Electronic and mechanical project development.

DIGISUB - PETROBRAS Abrp. 2019 - Oct. 2021

- 3D digitizer development project of underwater surfaces in deep water.
- Development of ROS nodes in C/C++ and Python language.
- Hardware and firmware development for actuator systems and peripheral communication.
- Prototype power system sizing: sources, AC-DC/DC-DC converters, batteries.

Polytechnic School of the Federal University of Bahia - UFBA

Salvador, BA Dec. 2018 - Dec. 2022

- 1 GigE communication development between FPGA and ROS.
- Hardware project in verilog for implementation in SOC/FPGA (Cyclone V Intel).
- Socket programming in C/C++ language for linux.
- Development of ROS nodes in C/C++ language.
- Paper presented at <u>IBERCHIP 2022</u>.

Faculty of Science and Technology - ÁREA1

Salvador BA Jul. 2011 - Jul. 2013

INICIAÇÃO CIENTÍFICA

MASTER'S PROJECT

Development of a microcontrolled command to fit old X-ray equipment to current technical standards.

- Programming 8051 family microcontrollers in assembly language.
- Research of the technical standards established by ANVISA in relation to X-ray equipment.
- · Presentation of monthly reports with activities developed in the period.
- Publication of the results in an article in the journal Cientefico ISSN 1677-1591, jul/dez 2013.

Competências e Habilidades

Básico Verilog HDL, Cyclone V, Sockets, Cmake, GDB, Nios II, FreeRTOS, Embedded Linux, SimuLink. Intermediário Python, 3D CAD, ARM Cortex M, Quartus Prime, Linux, Git/Github, PIC, AutoCAD, ROS/Gazebo.

Avançado PCB/KiCad, Matlab, C/C++, AVR, 8051, GNU-Make, LaTeX.

Presentation

28th IBERCHIP Workshop

Santiago, Chile

1-4 Mar. 2022

IEEE CIRCUITS AND SYSTEMS SOCIETY IN LATIN AMERIACA

• Comunicação entre Robot Operating System - ROS e SoC com FPGA integrado